Guide to the Jeanne Audrey Powers Papers RL.10181
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Materials, 1970-2004 and undated
  - Pamphlets, Articles, and Clippings
    - In God's Image - Spring 1993 (Box 83)
    - In God's Image - Winter 1992 (Box 83)
    - In God's Image - Autumn 1992 (Box 83)
    - One World: A Monthly Magazine of the World Council of Churches - 1991 (Box 83)
    - One World: A Monthly Magazine of the World Council of Churches - 1990 (Box 83)
    - Open Hands: Journal of the Reconciling Congregation Program: Sexuality and Spirituality - Winter 1988 (Box 83)
    - The Christian Century - March 1978 (Box 83)
    - Response: United Methodist Women: Special Assembly Issue - July/August 1978 (Box 83)
    - The Christian Century - December 1976 (Box 83)
    - Response: United Methodist Women - December 1975 (Box 83)
    - Response: United Methodist Women - December 1976 (Box 83)
    - One World: A Monthly Magazine of the World Council of Churches - May 1977 (Box 83)
    - New World Outlook: The Mission Magazine of the United Methodist Church - November/December 1994 (Box 83)
    - New World Outlook - June 1982 (Box 83)
    - Open Hands: Reconciling Ministries With Lesbians and Gay Men - Summer 1989 (Box 83)
    - Alive Now! - November/December 1983 (Box 83)
    - The Flyer - 1974-1996 (Box 83)
    - Various Articles - Undated (Box 83)
    - Christian Literature/Newspaper Articles - 1977-1988 (Box 84)
    - Miscellaneous Articles - 1985-1988 (Box 84)
    - New World Outlook - May 1981 (Box 84)
    - Chapel of the Unnamed Faithful: Bibliographical Information on Persons Honored in the New Stained Glass Windows: Garrett-Evangelical Theological Seminary: Evanston, Illinois - ca. 1993 (Box 84)
    - Aware: Garrett-Evangelical Prepares for 'Bold Leaders' Campaign Kick-Off - April 1996 (Box 84)
    - Bold Leaders for a New World: Garrett-Evangelical Theological Seminary's Campaign for the Future - ca. 1994 (Box 84)
    - 'Shalom' Newsletters - 1994-2001 (Box 84)
    - Affirmation Newsletter - Undated (Box 84)
    - (RMN) Katalyst Newsletter - 1996-2009 (Box 84)
    - Independent Newsletters: Publishing - 1975-2006 (Box 84)
    - Protestants Offer a Ritual to Mark the End of Marriage - December 1976 (Box 84)
    - One World: A Monthly Magazine of the World Council of Churches - May 1977 (Box 84)
    - In God's Image - Summer 1995 (Box 84)
    - New World Outlook - January 1987 (Box 84)
    - The Episcopacy: A Painful Problem - December 1976 (Box 84)
    - Miscellaneous Articles - 1971-1996 (Box 84)
    - Clippings, Bulletins, Notes, Other Documents (Part 1 of 6) - 1963-1989 (Box 84)
    - Clippings, Bulletins, Notes, Other Documents (Part 2 of 6) - 1967-1992 (Box 85)
    - Clippings, Bulletins, Notes, Other Documents (Part 3 of 6) - 1976-1999 (Box 85)
    - Clippings, Bulletins, Notes, Other Documents (Part 4 of 6) - 1986-1991 (Box 85)
    - Clippings, Bulletins, Notes, Other Documents (Part 5 of 6) - 1976-2000 (Box 85)
    - Clippings, Bulletins, Notes, Other Documents (Part 6 of 6) - 1987-2008 (Box 85)
    - People Weekly - 1976 (Box 85)
    - The Christian Century - December 1976 (Box 83)
    - New World Outlook - January 1977 (Box 83)
- Re-Imagining Movement, 1993-2003
  Powers was an active member of the Re-Imagining Coordinating Council in the 1990s. This series includes the original petitions and materials related to the controversial Re-Imagining Conference and subsequent protests by women of faith.
  - Re-Imagining: Jesus, Christ, Us - 1994 (Box 88)
  - Re-Imagining: Jesus, Christ, Us - 1995 (Box 88)
  - Re-Imagining Conference - 1993 (Box 88)
  - A Time of Hope, A Time of Threat - 1994 (Box 88)
  - Re-Imagining: Presbyterian Conflict - 1994 (2 folders) (Box 88)
  - Church Society: Reimagining...God...Community...The Church: From the Ecumenical Decade Conference - November 1993 (Box 88)
  - Re-Imagining Conference - 1993 (Box 89)
  - Voices of Sophia - 1996 (Box 89)
  - Re-Imagining Planning Committee - 1991-1994 (Box 89)
  - Re-Imagining: Post Conference - ca. 1994 (Box 89)
  - Re-Imagining: The Nine of Us - 1994 (Box 89)
  - Photos: Jeanne Audrey - ca. 1994 (Box 89)
  - Re-Imagining: Secular Press - ca. 1994 (Box 89)
  - Wisdom - 1994 (Box 90)
  - Re-Imagining: Letters: Critical - 1994 (Box 90)
  - Re-Imagining: Letters of Support (mostly United Methodist) - 1993-1994 (Box 90)
  - Re-Imagining: Good News (and Their Crowd) Material - Undated (Box 90)
  - Re-Imagining: Institutional (Mainline) Responses (Box 90)
  - Re-Imagining: Mainline Religious Stores News - ca. 1994 (Box 91)
  - Re-Imagining: The Nine of Us: Press Conference - 1994 (Box 91)
  - Re-Imagining: Promotional Materials - ca. 1994 (Box 91)
  - Re-Imagining: Press Articles - 1993-1994 (Box 91)
  - Re-Imagining Conference - 1993 (Box 91)
  - Re-Imagining: Coordinating Council - 1994-2003 (Box 92)
  - Re-Imagining - 1994-1998 (Box 92)
  - Re-Imagining Backlash - 1994-2001 (Box 92)
  - Re-Imagining: "The Nine of Us": A Time of Hope, A Time of Threat - 1994-1996 (Box 92)
  - Re-Imagining "Sophia" - 1987-1996 (Box 92)
  - Re-Imagining: Presbyterian Response - 1994 (Box 92)
  - Re-Imagining: Reflections Analyses - 1994-1998 (Box 92)
  - Presp.: Voices of Sophia - 1996-2002 (Box 92)
  - Re-Imagining Community (1 of 3) - 2000-2003 (Box 92)
  - Re-Imagining Community (2 of 3) - 1994-1998 (Box 93)
  - Re-Imagining Community (3 of 3) - 1998-2000 (Box 93)
  - Sophia - 1995 (Box 93)
  - Re-Imagining Revival - 1998 (Box 93)
  - Red Thread Service - 1990-1991 (Box 93)
- Accession (2015-0177), 1955-2015 and undated
  - Professional, 1955-2015 and undated
    - Ordained Women, 1955-1981 (Box 94, Folder 1, 2)
    - Order of Worship (Programs), 1967-1968 (Box 94, Folder 3, 4)
    - Feminist Worship, 1969-2000 (Box 94, Folder 5, 6, Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Assorted Services, circa 1970s (Box 95, Folder 2, 3)
    - Worship Samples, Traditional & Non-traditional, 1970 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Sex Role Stereotyping, 1971-1975 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Women, Bible, Church History, 1971-1986 (Box 96, Folder 1, 2)
    - Women in Ministry, 1971-1998 (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Consciousness Raising, 1972-1976 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Worship Materials, 1972-1980 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Commission on Women in Ministry, 1973-1978 (Box 97, Folder 1, 2)
    - Feminist Sermons, 1973-1983 (Box 97, Folder 3, 4)
    - Episcopal Women Priests, 1974-1976 (Box 98, Folder 1, 5)
    - UM Soc. Of Worship, Music, and Arts, 1974-1980 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Vatican - Women Priests, 1974-1986 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Assorted Writings, 1975-2013 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Way, Daley, Ruether, 1975-1977 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Women of Faith, 1976-1989 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Women's History Project, 1979-1980 (Box 99, Folder 2, 3)
    - Theology, 1971-1978 (Box 99, Folder 4, Box 100, Folder 1)
    - International Association of Women Ministers (IAWM), 1976-2015 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Resources - Study Guides, 1980 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Sermons, 1980-1981 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Women of Faith, 1980-1990 (Box 100, Folder 5, 6)
    - Commission on the Status and Role of Women, 1982 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Women of Faith in the 80s, 1981-1985 (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - W.A.T.E.R., 1982-1990 (Box 101, Folder 2, 3)
    - Worship, 1984-1992 (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - UMC Women District Superintendents, 1985 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - The Fellowship of United Methodists in Worship, Music, and Other Arts, 1985-1991 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Hymnal, 1986-1988 (Box 101, Folder 7, 8)
    - Myers-Briggs Type Indicator, 1986 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Stephen Fink Memorial Service & Scholarship, 1989-2014 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Stephen Fink Memorial, 1989-2009 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Assorted Correspondence, 1990-1998 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - United Methodist Women Assembly - Cincinnati, 1992-1994 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - World Affairs Committee, 1995-2014 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Clergy Alliance of the Reconciling Ministries Network, 1996-2005 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Conferences, Correspondence, Articles, 1997-2015 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - CLOUT (Christian Lesbians OUT), 1998-2005 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Status & Role of Women, Religion, and Race, 1998-2010 (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Shower of Stoles, 2000-2012 (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Conferences, Correspondence, Articles, 2002-2008 (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - LGBT Religious Archives, 2002-2007 (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), Pomona Valley Chapter, 2003-2007 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Claremont UMC, 2003-2013 (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - Reconciling Retired Clergy Caucus, 2003-2006 (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - Shower of Stoles (Claremont), 2003-2005 (Box 103, Folder 9)
    - Tuell Speech (Reconciling Ministries Network), 2003-2010 (Box 103, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 2004-2015 (Box 103, Folder 11)
    - Good News, 2004-2012 (Box 103, Folder 12)
    - Judicial Council Bishop Action Results, 2004-2005 (Box 103, Folder 13)
    - Minnesota Reconciling Ministries Network, 2004-2006 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - UMC Worldwide Nature of the Church, 2004-2014 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Reconciling Ministries, 2005-2010 (Box 104, Folder 3, 4)
    - Women's Perspective Claremont, 2006-2009 (Box 104, Folder 5, 6)
    - Anti-Homophobia Resources, 2009 (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - Waterwheel Newsletter, 2009 (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - Amy Long, "An Altar Trial for All," (Bruce Robbins), 2011-2012 (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - Conference, UMC/Mel Talbert, 2012 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - 2014 Conference (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Reconciling Ministries Network, 2006-2014 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - UMC Reconciling Award, 2014 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - JAP Writings and Sermons, undated (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Methodist Federation for Social Action (MFSA), undated (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - MN Methodist Student Movement, undated (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - Transgender, undated (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - Worship, undated (Box 110, Folder 9)
    - Zionism, undated (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - Personal, 1932-2015 and undated
    - Mankato History, Blue Earth County, 1932-2012 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Mankato State Teachers College, Bachelor of Science Degree, 1954 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Dettman & Wegner Wedding, Other Weddings, 1963-1971 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Wedding Programs, 1963-1971 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1965-2014 (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Wedding Sermon, 1967 (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Assorted Photos, 1972-2011 (Box 105, Folder 7)
    - Articles, Poems, 1974-2012 (Box 105, Folder 8)
    - Sister Corita Kent, 1978-2012 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Thomas John Carlisle, 1981-1984 (Box 105, Folder 10)
    - Val Ford (Poems), 1981-1982 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - Florence Powers Memorial Service (JAP's mother), 1982 (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - Personal: Art, Photos, Cards, etc., 1982-2015 (Box 105, Folder 13)
    - Christmas Letters, 1988-2014 (Box 105, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1992-2004 (Box 105, Folder 15)
    - Gifts, 1993-2009 (Box 105, Folder 16)
    - Retirement, 1995-1996 (Box 105, Folder 17)
    - Candler Donations (Art & Books), 1996-2011 (Box 105, Folder 18)
    - Claremont School of Theology (CST), Bishops Event, 2003-2005 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Feminist Writings, 2003 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - Pilgrim Place Correspondence, 2004-2013 (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - Travels, 2004-2007 (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - Danforth "Danny Grad", 2005-2014 (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Hennepin Avenue United Methodist Church (HAUMC), [2006] (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - Chattel, 2007-2011 (Box 106, Folder 7)
    - Cape Cod, 2012-2015 (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - Holocaust Collection donation from JA Powers to United Theological Seminary (UTS), 2012 (Box 106, Folder 9)
    - Summit House, [2012] (Box 106, Folder 10)
    - Obituaries (Lyle T. Christianson), 2014 (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - Assorted Photos, undated (Box 106, Folder 12)
    - National Workshop on Christian Unity, Account of Deacon's Death, undated (Box 106, Folder 13)
    - Dr. Harry Denman, 1957-2010 (Box 105, Folder 19)
  - Printed Material, 1962-2015 and undated
    - Common Worship in the Christian Faith and Life Community, by Joseph Wesley Matthews, 1962 (Box 106, Folder 15)
    - Because We Are One People - Songs for Worship, 1974 (Box 106, Folder 16)
    - Ritual in a New Day - An Invitation, 1976 (Box 106, Folder 17)
    - Images of Life - An Invitation to Bible Study, 1982 (Box 106, Folder 18)
    - The Challenge to U.S. Churches Continues, 1990-1991 (Box 106, Folder 19)
    - Valentine Book, 1998 (Box 106, Folder 20)
    - The Loyal Opposition - Struggling with the Church on Homosexuality, edited by Tex Sample and Amy E. DeLong, 2000 (Box 106, Folder 21)
    - A Healing Divorce - Transforming the End of Your Relationship with Ritual and Ceremony, by Phil Penningroth & Barbara Penningroth, 2001 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Journeys That Opened Up the World - Women, Student Christian Movements, and Social Justice, 1955-1975, edited by Sara M. Evans, 2003 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Answering YES to God's Call - Doing Theology at Pilgrim Place, Volume Two, edited by Paul Kittlaus and Pat Patterson, 2006-2007 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Wising Up - Ritual Resources for Women of Faith in Their Journey of Aging, edited by Kathy Black & Heather Murray Elkins, 2005 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - The People's Story, by Jeanne Audrey Powers, undated (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Western Theology, by Wes Seeliger, undated (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - A 20th Century Folk Mass, by the Rev. Geoffray Beaumont, undated (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - Celebrate and Witness - Devotional Stories, Prayers and Poems of United Methodists, undated (Box 107, Folder 8)
    - 2005 Peace Calendar - "Let Us Go Forward Together," Preface by Howard Zinn (Box 107, Folder 9)
    - "Peace Loving Nations - Music of Peace and Resistance" 2006 Peace Calendar (Box 107, Folder 10)
    - War Resisters League 2007 Peace Calendar - "Screenpeace - An Antiwar Film Festival," Foreward by Jon Sayles (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - 2008 Peace Calendar - "Salaam Shalom Solh - Nonviolence and Resistance in the Middle East and Beyond," War Resisters League (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - 2009 Peace Calendar - "The Path of Most Resistance - A U.S. Radical History Tour" (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - 2010 Peace Calendar - "Sparking Change - Poster Art & Politics" (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - 2011 Peace Calendar - "Not Your Fodder! Organizing Against the Militarization of Youth" (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - 2012 Peace Calendar - "Organize This! A 1955-2011 Introspective," Foreward by Noam Chomsky (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - 2013 Diary (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - 2014 Day Planner (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - Motive Magazine, 1965 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - The People's Story, JAP Outline, 1970-1974 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Various Memoirs and Reflections, 1986-2007 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - Breast Plates: A 1994 Photo Calendar (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - Boston School of Theology: Focus, 2013-2015 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - Assorted Posters, Art, undated (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Creed, undated (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Re-Imagining, circa 1990s
    - Re-Imagining, circa 1990s (Box 106, Folder 14)